<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="46"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[2]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[BPD Report 2021 Fall














































                                                                                                               3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[BUSINESS PROGRAM DEVELOPEMENT (BPD) - 2021 Fall


              Purpose of the Committee:


                 To explore the following three questions and provide recommendations:
                    1.    Is accreditation the right path for the business program?
                    2.    Are we meeting student needs through articulation?

                    3.    How does Business 202* fit in with all these?


              Background:

                 Dean of HUB initiated a discussion around "Direction and Approach: Business
                 202*" on Wednesday, September 1, 2021, highlighting the three main areas

                 above.


              Member Expectations:

                  Committee members are expected to demonstrate a commitment to:

                         Respectful of each other within the committee and outside.
                         Work collaboratively to achieve the committee's purpose.

                         Providing a perspective of what is best for our students, faculty, and insti-
                          tute.
                               Allow others to offer opinions but be objective.

                               Listen to others but do not allow others to dictate the objectives.
                         Attend committee meetings and follow through on time on any commit-
                          ments.

                         Support the success of the project.


              Composition of the committee:

                         Muhammad Rahman

                         Wendy Nahrgang
                         Harish Gautam

                         Layth Matthews
                         Satinderjit Khatkar (Business Coordinator and ad-hoc member)
                         Jonathan Nyantakyi (Business Coordinator and ad-hoc member)


                                                                                                               5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Sponsor (Where the buck stops):

                  Dr. Jonathon Penny, Dean, School of Human Services, University Transfer, and

                  Business Studies.


               Roles and Responsibilities:


                  The committee chair (or designate) is responsible for:
                         calling the meetings, setting the agenda and sending notices to committee
                          members,

                         ensuring the purpose/deliverables of the committee are achieved.

                         Committee members are responsible for contributing to the committee
                          work.
               Meetings:


                          Friday 9:00 - 10:00 A.M,

                         Monday 2:00 - 3:00 P.M.

               Term of the Committee:


                          Fall 2021 Semester


               Reporting/Communication:


                         Single point of communication (TBD)

                         Formal weekly/bi-weekly reporting to the Dean.

               Decision Making:


                  The committee will endeavour to work to consensus in decisions around the
                  work undertaken, but final decisions will be made by the Dean and Acting Asso-

                  ciate Dean.











              6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Methodology














































                                                                                                               9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[METHODOLOGY

                 Purpose of the study


                    The main assigned purpose to the BPD committee was to conduct an explora-
                    tive research in the following three areas and provide report and recommenda-
                    tions:

                       1. Is accreditation the right path for the business program?
                       2. Are we meeting student needs through articulation?

                       3. How does Business 202* fit in with all these?


                 Research Methodology


                    For achieving the assigned objectives of the project, the BPD team made a re-

                    search plan. This plan consisted of designing a questionnaire based survey, con-
                    ducting follow-up meetings with faculty members for individual discussions, ana-
                    lyzing the results and presenting the report to the faculty and submitting the fi-

                    nal report to the chair before the deadline. This involved the following major
                    steps as execution plan -


                    1.    Survey Questionnaire

                    2.    Follow-up Discussions with Faculty (based on faculty’s option)
                    3.    Talk with Experts

                              Articulation Officer

                              Aboriginal Recruitment Officers
                    4.    Analysis and Recommendations

                    5.    Presentation of the report to the business faculty

                    6.    Submission of final report to the chair/Dean.


                 Survey Questionnaire:


                 The BPD team prepared a questionnaire with an aim to cover all

                 the major objectives of the research. The questionnaire consisted
                 of both open-ended (65%) and close-ended (35%) questions. BPD
                 team invited all the 23 faculty members to participate in an anony-


                                                                                                              11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[mous and confidential research by providing an online questionnaire between
                 October 5 to 11. Approximately 60% of the population, 14 out of 23 faculty mem-

                 bers, responded to the questionnaire (including one incomplete questionnaire).


                 Scope of the study


                 The study was conducted based on the valuable inputs from the faculty mem-
                 bers who were available to engage and respond.


                 Limitations of the study


                   There was no influx of inputs beyond CNC’s think tank. This study is limited on-
                    ly to the in-house reservoir of thoughts from the faculty and experts

                    (articulation officer and Aboriginal recruitment officer) and these are absolutely
                    important and valued. Expert talks from a neutral speaker for accreditation
                    and someone from UNBC for articulation could have added another perspec-

                    tive.


                   The student survey could have been a critical part of the research data, be-
                    cause everything in this project was revolving around the student interest; but

                    due to short span, it was not feasible to create a sampling plan and execute it.


                   The time for the study was a limiting factor. It was challenging for BPD mem-
                    bers to justify teaching with this project, even though there was the release
                    time granted for this purpose.


                   Due to COVID restrictions in place were another limiting factor, in person in-

                    teractions were not possible.























              12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Analysis of Data














































                                                                                                              13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Q1: Do you feel that CNC business program needs improvement?





















                 Findings

                  Based on the very basic objective of this project, the questionnaire’s first ques-

                  tion was explorative in nature. The close-ended question stated, if the respond-
                  ing faculty member feels that the business program needs improvements. As

                  expected, the majority of the 85.71 percent of the respondents felt that CNC
                  business program requires improvements, while rest of the 14.29% were not

                  too sure.






























                                                                                                              15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Q2: What changes would you like to make in CNC business program and why?















































































              16]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Q3: What do you like about the CNC business program?









































                   Findings


                      Majority of 41% of the Business Faculty at
                       CNC liked the CNC business program be-
                       cause of its applied approach.

                      35% respondents believed that the best
                       part of the CNC business program is the
                       dedicated faculty.


                      Just about, 18% respondents felt that, the best part of the program is the stu-
                       dents who are motivated and dedicated learners.
                      While 6% respondents believed that flexible approach of CNC business pro-
                       gram makes it better than any other institution,  e.g., it is not mandatory for
                       students to complete it in two years in a cohort style program.












                                                                                                              17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Q4: Do you think CNC students require more time and support than university
                    students?































                   Findings


                    A majority of 61.54% of the respondents believed that CNC students require

                    more time and support than university students. On the other hand, 38.46%
                    were of the viewpoint that CNC students are not different from the university
                    students, thus there should be no extra time given to CNC students.


                    In order to dig deeper, the questionnaire imposed an open-ended question to let
                    faculty members reflect on the reasoning behind their thoughts.




























              18]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Q5: Please elaborate on your answer of the previous question. (Please explain
                   why and provide any examples you can think of.)




                                                                                    *Analysis Note—Some of the
                                                                                    respondents did not answer clear-
                                                                                    ly in favour of more hours or
                                                                                    against it, rather they shared both
                                                                                    sides of the coin. Thus for the
                                                                                    purpose of the analysis instead of
                                                                                    counting the percentage of faculty
                                                                                    members in favour or against the
                                                                                    analysis is based on the number
                                                                                    of arguments that went against
                                                                                    and in favour of this discussion.








                   Findings


                   There were very interesting
                   thoughts shared by the faculty,

                   both in favour and against.
                   Both schools of thoughts
                   strongly believed that their ap-

                   proach is in the best interest of
                   students. Those in favour, justi-

                   fied spending more time is important for the student success.


                   While others suggested that business faculty should
                   work on making the business program more structured,
                   and it should be focused on effective delivery and self-

                   directed instructions to the students so that they are
                   ready for the university.



                   Think tank’s suggestions ->






                                                                                                              19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Q6: Approximately 26% of the CNC business students transfer to UNBC, what
                   do you think about creating an alternative track (independent of our exist-

                   ing business diploma) that better meets UNBC lower division B. Comm. re-
                   quirements?


                   The figure of 26% of the CNC business students trans-

                   fer to UNBC was based on the inputs received from
                   the articulation officer from the registrar’s office. This
                   triggered a strong reason to make CNC courses seam-

                   lessly transferable. Mixed responses came from the
                   faculty— some faculty members strongly believed

                   that it is a good idea, especially when it is important for the students. But, CNC’s
                   existing program might also be adding some value to the rest of the students.
                   Thus, there were suggestions to explore the possibility of adding a separate track

                   for UT. This option might attract more domestic students as they will get maxi-
                   mum credits earned at CNC transferred to UNBC or some other institutions.


                                                                     While others believed that it would

                                                                    be a wasteful effort, and most of the
                                                                    thoughts were to be cautious not to
                                                                    target solely on the needs of one

                                                                    (UNBC) university. There were some
                                                                    inputs regarding similar efforts done

                                                                    in the past to facilitate CNC to UNBC
                                                                    direct transfer that did not mature.


                  Justification of analysis - there were some responses reflecting both the sides of
                   the coin - making it hard for analysis to count percentage of respondents in fa-

                   vour or against this. Thus, for the purpose of analysis instead of respondents, the
                   actual count of arguments, responses in favour or against, were counted. In total,

                   six arguments were in the favour of creating a separate track, while ten were
                   against the idea of creating a separate track.










              20]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Q7: What changes (if any) would you make in the current program to better
                   prepare students that are entering the workforce?









































                   Findings


                   Responses to this question
                   sprouted wonderful ideas. Most

                   of the faculty respondents sug-
                   gested that the business pro-
                   gram should engage more with

                   the local business community.
                   As per responses, such engage-

                   ments might facilitate students
                   in getting work-integrated learn-
                   ing (WIL) and getting inputs from the business community to update the course

                   curriculum. Also, there were suggestions to develop an entrepreneurial and
                   placement cell to support the business students.







                                                                                                              21]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Q8: Would you be willing to adjust your courses to make them more transfera-
                   ble?






































                   Findings


                   Faculty members were willing to make changes if they believe that these changes

                   are for the good of the students. Majority of 62% responses were strongly agree-
                   ing without any question or condition to make changes to their courses, while

                   others would do it depending on importance and need of bringing in such
                   change for the good of students.


                   Sometimes, it is good to have some third-party standardization authority to navi-
                   gate the changes in the right directions for the good of our students. One such

                   authority in this direction could be accreditation. BPD wanted to know from the
                   faculty if they are aware of accreditation as a next question in this direction.














              22]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Q9: Do you feel you are familiar with accreditation and its pros and cons?
























                   Findings


                   Majority of 54 percent respondents were not too sure if they confidently know
                   about accreditation. While 31 percent said that know if pros and cons of the ac-

                   creditation. The rest of the 15 percent respondents had no idea about accredita-
                   tion’s pros or cons and what it would mean for CNC.





              Q10: Would you be interested in learning more about accreditation and its im-
                    plications for our program?



                   As expected, majority of

                   92.31% responses from
                   business faculty mem-

                   bers showed interest in
                   learning more about ac-
                   creditation and its impli-

                   cations for business pro-
                   gram at CNC.




                                                                                                              23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Q11: Would you be willing to volunteer for a committee in your subject area for
                     continuous improvement of your program/courses?




























                   A majority of 76.92 percent business faculty members responded that they
                   would be willing to volunteer for a committee in their subject area for the pur-

                   pose of continuous improvement of their courses and the program. While, 23.08
                   percent did not want to volunteer for a committee in their subject area for con-

                   tinuous improvement of program.





              Q13: Are you willing to speak to us further about your answers?

                   For the purpose of getter better understanding and insight of business faculty,
                   BPD team invited the respondents for engaging in a follow-up discussion around

                   these topics in the questionnaire. BPD team invited everyone if they wish to en-
                   gage in individual discussion, and once again this discussion would be kept confi-
                   dential.


                   BPD team appreciate that 76.92 percent of the faculty members were interested

                   in meeting. The BPD team organized a scheduled questionnaire based meeting
                   consisting of two members from BPD group and one interested faculty members

                   individually. These meetings were both in person and via zoom as per the con-
                   venience of the faculty members.






              24]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Recommendations








































                                                                                                              25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[26]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[REFLECTION AND RECOMMENDATIONS





                   All the collected responses, using an online questionnaire and follow-up discus-

                   sion sessions with business faculty members, were compelling. On the top of
                   this, eye-opening inputs came from the talks with experts — Laura Buchi, Articu-
                   lation Officer from the Office of the Registrar office and Patricia Prince and  Dawn

                   George, the Aboriginal Recruitment Officers at CNC.



                   The BPD team boiled down all their thoughts and is submitting its report and rec-
                   ommendations to the dean’s office for any further action plan. For the purpose

                   of keeping it organized the recommendations are divided into following sections.


              1)    BPD REPORT ON ABORIGINAL STUDENTS


              2)













































                                                                                                              27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[BPD REPORT ON ABORIGINAL STUDENTS



                   In order to ensure the progressive approach of Business Pro-
                   grams in the right directions, it is important to focus on Aborigi-

                   nal student needs and problems. So, with an aim to get critical
                   feedback to improve, the BPD group met with Aboriginal Re-

                   cruiting Officers at CNC —  Patricia Prince and Dawn George.
                   The following are the inferences based on the discussions held
                   with Aboriginal Recruiting officers, as well as suggestions

                   from the business faculty.


                Let’s start with these Positive Vibes

                   COVID has forced many changes in all spheres of professional life, teaching,

                   and delivery of instructions to students is not untouched.  One such big change
                   resulted in Hybrid and HyFlex learning model with an advantage of both online

                   and face to face instructions with great flexibility.


                     Aboriginal students experienced  HyFlex and Hybrid model of teaching as a
                       convenient approach to learning because it allows them to choose not to

                       leave their community for the purpose of study. Students are opting and
                       switching to the courses that are offered online so that they can stay with

                       their community while studying.


                     Further on this, there is recommendation that during post-pandemic scenar-
                       io, it might be a good idea to have some class sections online and face to face
                       (F2F) e.g., two sections F2F and one section may be online. It will facilitate stu-

                       dents choosing whether they want to come to Prince George in campus or
                       want to have it accessible online remotely.



                     There may be an opportunity to use the remote setups that might already be
                       existing in territories and arrange DDI like setup by optimally utilizing their
                       community’s existing resources.





              28]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Problems/Challenges Faced by Aboriginal Student Population


                   Transferability issues : After completion of CNC diploma, the CNC students end
                      up not meeting the requirements for other universities, especially University of

                      Northern British Columbia (UNBC).


                   Lack of Flexibility : Core and business elective combinations leave less room for
                      students to pick University Transfer (UT) courses.


                   Challenging to succeed : In the beginning, students hope to get business and

                      accounting related courses with the hope to find an office job, but somehow
                      courses like Accounting and Math seem to become challenging for them. Abo-

                      riginal students end up shifting from Accounting to Management courses.



              Suggestions/Recommendations


                   Sponsorship : There are some third-party funders, it’s not just band funders,

                      rather there are recipients of social assistance or EI. It is important to be cogni-
                      zant that some sponsors won’t allow students anything beyond what is men-
                      tioned/listed in the requirements of the course, for e.g., calculator, laptop, etc.

                      So it is recommended to add some standard list of tools required to be suc-
                      cessful for a business programs so that students face no problem to seek ap-

                      proval from their sponsors.


                   Credits and hours : Even though there is a separate report regarding hours,
                      this one is related to Aboriginal students in particular. Some bands have spe-
                      cific requirement policies as to how many courses students need to take in a

                      semester. It might be overwhelming for aboriginal students to cope up with all
                      this. On top of that, longer credit hours required to earn such courses/credits

                      would make it challenging for aboriginal students due to their specific condi-
                      tions and socio-economic gaps that exist.


                   Pre-Business Access : Investigate BC Adult dogwood program’s math require-

                      ments and design access to pre-business access options.



                                                                                                              29]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[  Block transfer : As aboriginal recruiting officer, Patricia would like to know if

                      students can’t get transferred to UNBC where else they could be guided for.
                      So, any kind of agreement with UNBC or any other university to have block

                      transfer for the courses would be a great value addition.


                   Aboriginal students join the business program with entrepreneurial mindset
                      and with the hope to develop their own business, it requires some support
                      for such students. CE courses do not work for band sponsored students be-

                      cause it is not accredited.


                   Further, in order to seek direct feedback from

                      aboriginal students, consider working with
                      Bruce Allan, Aboriginal Studies Instructor. In
                      might be organizing a talking circle event with

                      Aboriginal students to seek direct feedback in
                      order to understand their challenges and im-

                      prove the courses and programs.


              BPD Suggestion-

                 It is blurry to say what do we need to do in order to move our course delivery

                 more towards indigenisation. After discussion with various members, it seems
                 that we all might  already be doing it. So, it is recommended to -




                   Carefully craft and professionally draft some text as an acknowledgement to
                      traditional territories of CNC campus locations.


                   This acknowledgement text may be in the form of some kind of paragraph to

                      be included in our course outlines, and let it be a standard part of template
                      for all the courses at business.


                   It may be a small step and signal a sense of respect and welcoming attitude of

                      inclusion by CNC to all students in the class.







              30]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS


              Our Special thanks to all of you who provided us the valuable inputs/support  -


                 Laura Buchi, Articulation Officer from the Office of the Registrar, deserves the

                 heartiest thanks for all the valuable inputs she provided BPD team during the
                 whole process of the research.


                 We also want to acknowledge special thanks to Patricia Prince and  Dawn
                 George, the Aboriginal Recruitment Officers at CNC, for all the valuable inputs with

                 regard to challenges and recommendations focusing to Aboriginal business stu-
                 dents.


                 Special thanks to the sponsor of this project, Dr. Jonathon Penny, Dean, School
                 of Human Services, University Transfer, and Business Studies. Muhammad Rehman,

                 for actively engaging, arranging all the resources, both as a member of BPD as
                 well as in capacity of acting associate dean. Thanks to both of the coordinators
                 Satinderjit Khatkar and Jonathan Nyantakyi  for providing BPD team special

                 slots in all the monthly meetings and arranging final presentation session.


                 Above all, BPD team want to acknowledge the valuable contribution of all the
                 Business Faculty members for submitting their responses by filling the ques-

                 tionnaires and also for engaging with BPD team during the follow-up discussion
                 sessions. Without your contribution, this project was impossible. We all in the
                 BPD team, learned a lot from all the faculty members and heartiest thanks for all

                 the time and valuable inputs. THANK YOU EVERYONE!!





              BPD Team
              Fall 2021.















                                                                                                              31]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[32]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Annexure








































                                                                                                              33]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[34]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Presentation by:                                                    Laura Buchi,



                                                                        Articulation Officer,


                                                                    Office of the Registrar










                                                                                                              35]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[36]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[37]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[38]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[39]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[40]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[41]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[42]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[43]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[44]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[45]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[46]]></page></pages></Search>